<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on le quotidien</title>
    <link>http://lipeggy.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on le quotidien</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 03:25:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lipeggy.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy a Book, Make a Donation</title>
      <link>http://lipeggy.com/post/buy-books-donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 03:25:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lipeggy.com/post/buy-books-donate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2014, I was reflecting on my year and thinking about ways to optimize my time management, learning, personal finance, and other habits in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized I have a tendency to buy a lot of books (read [no pun intended]: I rarely walk into a bookstore and leave empty-handed) that I never actually end up reading/finishing. As much as I love accumulating interesting books and supporting local bookstores, I want to be mindful of my spending and also find and leverage opportunities to build more good habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I came up with a simple new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions:  &lt;strong&gt;for every book purchase I make, I would donate to charity.&lt;/strong&gt; [1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t set amounts, thresholds, or other complex rules. I could define a purchase as &amp;ldquo;per-book&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;per-order&amp;rdquo; online / &amp;ldquo;per-visit&amp;rdquo; in-store. I could donate $5 or $50. I could donate to any organization, as long as I was reasonably confident that it was going to a good cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I started off with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kiva.org/&#34;&gt;Kiva&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.watsi.org&#34;&gt;Watsi&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by the idea of micro-lending since I first heard about Muhammad Yunus and the Grameen Bank back in high school, so Kiva was a natural first choice. I especially love how both platforms share the stories of individual people whom you can support, which creates both a feeling of greater transparency and a stronger human connection. (I actually joined the Watsi Universal Fund, but still receive and love receiving emails about whom a donation goes to support!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, especially after the Nepal earthquake, I was interested in finding larger global organizations to support as well. Sites like &lt;a href=&#34;www.charitynavigator.org&#34;&gt;Charity Navigator&lt;/a&gt; have been an invaluable resource in removing one of my biggest mental barriers to making more charitable donations: finding fiscally responsible organizations with meaningful missions that make a real impact on the communities that need it most. While these are probably extreme examples, these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/20/business/4-cancer-charities-accused-in-ftc-fraud-case.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;four scam cancer charities&lt;/a&gt; are precisely what I hope to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say (hopefully), I&amp;rsquo;m really pleased with how this has been going so far. No, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been going through my booklog (&lt;code&gt;echo backlog | sed s/back/book/&lt;/code&gt;) any faster – if anything, I spend slightly more time online looking for and learning about interesting, impactful, and inspiring organizations that are doing good around the world. But I truly, deeply hope that making this small tweak to a personal habit will, directly or indirectly, help positively impact somebody else&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] This is not at all meant to imply that I want to be very frugal and neither buy books nor donate. I actually do the former at about the same rate, but now I regularly do the latter as well. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>